Guide to the Allan R. Holmberg collection on Peru, circa 1946-1966.
Holmberg, Allan R., collection on Peru, circa 1946-1966
- Series II. Cornell Peru Project (Accession 2)
  - Manifesto del Comite Ejecutivo Departamental del Partido Aprista Peruano de Ancash: Caso Vicos, 1959 (Box 22, Folder 18)
  - Sociology and Anthropology 281: Middle and South America Seminar (Box 21, Folder 26)
  - Summer field studies program applicants, 1964 (Box 21, Folder 27)
  - General information on Recuayhuanca, Marcara, 1951 (Box 21, Folder 28)
  - Land titles (Recuayhuanca, Virhuez); Recuayhuanca census (Box 21, Folder 29)
  - "El Indigena y el Mestizo en la Comunidad de Marcara," Humberto Ghersi Barrera, thesis, 1953 (Box 21, Folder 30-31)
  - Lecture notes, outline for studying Vicos (Box 21, Folder 32)
  - Vicos-writings, notes and outlines (Box 21, Folder 33)
  - Miscellaneous notes (Box 21, Folder 34)
  - Essays on Vicos (Box 21, Folder 35)
  - Manuscripts of research by others (Box 21, Folder 36)
  - "Prospectus for Research on a Localized Pilot Plant in a Subsistence Area of Peru", December 12, 1953 (Box 21, Folder 37)
  - Writings by Dobyns, Doughty, and others (Box 21, Folder 38-39)
  - "A Projective Typing Test Technique" by Henry Dobyns and Jane Fearer (Box 21, Folder 40)
  - Manuscripts on the public image of President John F. Kennedy in Peru (Box 21, Folder 41)
  - Memorandum for the Honorable Mr. Adlai Stevenson on the Social and Economic Development of the Andean Indian Population, 1961 (Box 21, Folder 42)
  - Padron General de Comunidades Indigenas Reconocidas Oficialmente, June 1961 (Box 21, Folder 43)
  - "Vicos and the Peace Corps," Richard W. Patch, 1964 (Box 21, Folder 44)
  - Perception by B. Lourie, "The Big Man" (Box 21, Folder 45)
  - "The Varayoc System in Vicos," Mario C. Vazquez, January 1964 (Box 21, Folder 46)
  - "Agricultural and Related Innovation in Vicos," William W. Stein, November 1969 (Box 21, Folder 47)
  - Vicos: An Experiment in Social Change (a Resource Unit for Grade 5), August 1965 (Box 21, Folder 48)
  - "Changing community attitudes and values in Peru," Holmberg, photo book manuscript (Box 21, Folder 49)
  - "Participant Intervention in the Field," Holmberg (Box 21, Folder 50)
  - "Some Experiments in Socioeconomic Change in an Underdeveloped Area," Allan R. Holmberg (Box 21, Folder 51)
  - Castas of Vicos-paper drafts (Box 21, Folder 52)
  - "The Castas: Unilinear Kin Groups in Vicos, Peru" by Vazquez and Holmberg (Box 21, Folder 53)
  - "Linguistic Research in Latin America: The Peruvian Andes," Donald Sola, 1958 (Box 21, Folder 54)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1950-1960 (Box 22, Folder 19)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1960-1962 (Box 22, Folder 20)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1951, 1957-1966 (Box 22, Folder 21-27)
  - Periodicals Vicos, 1950s (Box 22, Folder 28)
  - "Vicos: Boletin Informativo", 1957 (Box 22, Folder 29)
  - "Noticiero Vicos: Boletin Informativo de la 'Junta de Delegados' ", June-September 1959 (Box 22, Folder 30)
  - "Peru: Nu smiler indianerne igen" in Hjemmet [in Norwegian], July 26, 1966 (Box 14)
  - A. Pinilla Concha, newspaper clippings (Box 22, Folder 31)
  - Humberto Ghersi Barrera-collected historical Peruvian documents (Box 22, Folder 32)
  - Political and cultural flyers, Callejon de Huaylas (Box 22, Folder 33)
  - Miscellaneous Peruvian newspaper clippings and political broadsides, 1950s (Box 22, Folder 34)
  - Newspaper commentaries on culture in Peru, 1955 (Box 22, Folder 35)
  - Peru-politics, 1950s (Box 22, Folder 36)
  - Education-Peru (newspaper clippings) (Box 22, Folder 37)
  - Archeology-Peru (newspaper clippings) (Box 22, Folder 38)
  - Economic-Peru (newspaper clippings) (Box 22, Folder 39)
  - Collazos C., Carlos, et al., "Dietary Surveys in Peru" I and II, 1953-1954 (Box 22, Folder 40)
- Series III. Viru
  The materials in this series were sent to the archives with the Series II. Cornell Peru Project (Accession 2) materials. They mostly consist of correspondence and subject files relating to Allan Holmberg's research in Viru, Peru, especially regarding fiestas.
  - Broadsides of fiestas in Viru area, 1960 (Box 17, Folder 81)
  - Carol Lee Bengelsdorf, "Medical Practices in Viru", 1965 (Box 17, Folder 82)
  - Amanda D. McMahon, "Women in the Community in Viru, Peru", 1965 (Box 17, Folder 83)
  - Paper on dancing in Viru (Box 17, Folder 84)
  - Thomas C. Greaves, "Puente de Viru, A Highway Community on the Peruvian North Coast" (Box 17, Folder 85)
  - Mario C. Vazquez, "Viru: Land and Society", 1964 (Box 17, Folder 86)
  - Research data, glossary, other papers and notes, 1947, 1961 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Essays, Folder 1 of 2 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Essays, Folder 2 of 2 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, 1964, 1966 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Studies of fiestas (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Fiestas and siestas paper (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Fiestas (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Introduction to Viru manuscript (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - "Viru in the colonial period" typescript (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Colonial period draft (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Manuscript chapter one (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Notes (Box 18, Folder 10-11)
  - Birth rate data, 1940-1947 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Field notebooks, circa 1947 (Box 18, Folder 13-16)
  - "Fiesta and Siesta in a Peruvian Town," table of contents and introduction (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Fiesta and Siesta
    - Senor de la Sangre (Box 18, Folder 18)
    - Senor de Huaman (Box 18, Folder 19)
    - San Isidro (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Corpus and Octava (Box 18, Folder 20)
    - Virgin of Sorrows (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Nuestra Senora del Carmen (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - Notes on fiestas, 1946 (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - Key to Name Code (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - Teaching materials (Box 18, Folder 24)
  - Land holdings (Box 18, Folder 25)
  - Tables on nutrition and demographics (Box 18, Folder 26)
  - Various field notes and questionnaire results (Box 18, Folder 27)
  - Totales del censo tomado en la comunidad del Viru, 1947-1948 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Miscellaneous notes and papers (Box 18, Folder 28)
  - "Ethnography of Politics in Viru" (Box 18, Folder 29)
  - Field notes by students in CPP summer program, 1964 (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Genealogies; census data sheet (Mapcase-folder 7)
  - Map, "The Central Andes" and CPP locations (Box 30)
  - Nuestro Senor de la Sangre, 1960 (Box 30)
- Series IV. The Cornell Methodology Project
  Material in this series relates to the administration and study design of the Cornell Methodology Project, conducted by the Department of Sociology. Field studies in Vicos were done in the summer of 1953. Vicos was chosen as the site because facilities established at the field station and information already gathered cut down the preparation and cost necessary to get the project underway. The analysis and processing of the field notes was done in Ithaca in 1954-1955. Edward A. Suchman headed the entire Cross-Cultural Methodology Project and Rose K. Goldsen directed the field operations in Vicos. She was assisted by Richard Patch and Bryce Ryan, and had three men to do the interviewing, plus one to collect life histories.
  - Administration and Operation in Vicos, Ancash, Peru
    This subseries contains three groupings of materials based on types of information generated by the project. The first group contains lists of informants and respondents compiled from various censuses and surveys to determine who among the Vicosinos had been interviewed, what their status was, and in which zone of Vicos they lived. The second group consists of material pertaining to the development of the study design, classification system, and qualitative survey interview as well as the design of the four Tareas or field tasks for testing the effects of variations in interview techniques. The third group contains coding information for the qualitative survey and for the 1952 household and individual census.
    - Lists of Informants and Respondents
      - a. Vicos Master Lists, Survey Sample, Call Sheets, Previous Call Lists b. Vicosinos-census list f. lists, 1953 (Box 12, Folder 1)
      - a. Systema de Llamar a los Peones b. peones labor-daily records f. lists, 1953 (Box 12, Folder 2)
      - a. PIAS respondents b. Vicosinos listed by zones f. lists, 1953 (Box 12, Folder 3)
      - a. Vicos names mentioned in interviews b. Vicosinos mentioned in Methodology interviews f. lists (Box 12, Folder 4)
      - a. Index of informants, respondents b. Vicosinos mentioned in Tareas 1 and 2 non-survey respondents f. lists (Box 12, Folder 5)
      - a. Vicos survey: lists of survey respondents b. Heads of households, qualitative survey card format f. lists (Box 12, Folder 6)
      - a. Index of names of informants covered by qualitative methods b. Vicosino names corrected from tareas f. lists (Box 12, Folder 7)
      - a. Movilizables b. Army reservists f. list, 1953 (Box 12, Folder 8)
      - a. Those who accepted NSP b. new seed potato acceptors f. lists, correspondence, 1952-1954 (Box 12, Folder 9)
      - a. Vicos Qualitative Information Index b. Vicosinos summary case reports f. bound volume of questionnaires, 1953 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Development of Classification System and Analytic Models
      - a. Rating Sheet for Qualitative Data, Vicos b. qualitative survey variables--comments f. lists, questionnaires (Box 12, Folder 11)
      - a. Vicos Survey Mortality b. unusable survey interviews f. notes, questionnaires (Box 12, Folder 12)
      - a. Vicos: Categories for Qualitative Material b. cross-referenced categories drafts f. lists (Box 12, Folder 13)
      - a. Vicos Qualitative Data, Development of Classification code b. classification system, drafts; cross referenced categories, drafts; classification system, frame of references; classification system, final form f. lists, memorandum, outlines, questionnaire, 1954 (Box 12, Folder 14)
      - a. Classification System for Vicos Qualitative Data b. classification system f. outline, 1954-1955 (Box 12, Folder 15)
      - a. Vicos: Instructions Given to Field Workers for Tareas b. Tareas I-IV field instructions. f. handbook (unbound), 1953 (Box 12, Folder 16)
      - a. Vicos: training workers, instructions b. field training, seed potato tarea variables code, community change f. pamphlet, outlines, questionnaires, 1953-1962 (Box 12, Folder 17)
      - a. Inventory of Vicos Qualitative Data b. qualitative data processing procedure, Quechua terms f. reports, lists, 1954-1955 (Box 12, Folder 18)
      - a. TAT's b. Thematic Apperception Test, instructions to tester f. notes, test (Box 12, Folder 19)
      - a. Story Line for Qualitative Data-Vicos b. new seed potato introduction comments on analysis c. Blanchard, William C. f. correspondence, report, 1955 (Box 12, Folder 20)
      - a. Comparative Analysis of Acceptance of NSP b. new seed potato introduction, new seed potato acceptors-1952, agricultural innovation f. correspondence, reports, 1955 (Box 12, Folder 21)
      - a. Vicos: Hand Talkies b. qualitative survey responses f. notes, lists (Box 12, Folder 22)
      - a. Development of Vicos Survey Questionnaire b. qualitative survey drafts, Tarea #4 objectives, interview techniques, technological innovation f. questionnaires, notes, memorandum, outline, 1953 (Box 12, Folder 23)
      - a. Development of Vicos Survey Questionnaire b. qualitative survey drafts, qualitative survey recommended revisions, Quechua terms f. questionnaires, notes, memorandum, 1953 (Box 12, Folder 24)
      - a. Survey Interview Form, Outline of Tareas b. qualitative survey, Tareas I-IV instructions, study design f. outlines, questionnaire, 1952-1953 (Box 12, Folder 25)
      - a. RKG Progress Report and Study Design 1953 b. field study analysis of objectives and technique, field interviewers evaluation, structured vs. unstructured interview technique c. Goldsen. Rose K.; Suchman, Edward A. f. correspondence, outline, report, 1953-1955 (Box 12, Folder 26)
      - a. Soler Tareas #2-3. Survey Questionnaires b. Qualitative Survey recommendations, Qualitative Survey responses, Seed Potato tarea variables code, classification system f. lists, questionnaires, outline, notes, 1953-1954 (Box 12, Folder 27)
      - a. Barnett School Children Study b. sociometric survey of school children f. questionnaire, 1953 (Box 12, Folder 28)
      - a. Goldsen--Tarea #3--memo, Patch-notes b. study design, field training f. memoranda, outline, notes, 1953 (Box 12, Folder 29)
      - a. Vicos Survey Introduction b. surveys f. questionnaires, note, 1953 (Box 12, Folder 30)
      - a. Ryan Tareas, democracy, Development of Questionnaires b. study design, democratic values analysis, cross-cultural methodology study design, interview techniques, technological innovation f. memoranda, outlines, questionnaires, 1953 (Box 12, Folder 31)
      - a. RKG-Correspondence and Problem of Cross-Cultural Equivalence of Data b. cross-cultural methodology study design, debriefing field workers, India and Thailand field study recommendations c. Goldsen, Rose K.; Ralis, Max; Suchman, Edward A. f. telegrams, correspondence, 1954 (Box 12, Folder 32)
      - a. RKG-Correspondence and Problem of Cross-Cultural Equivalence of Data b. cross-cultural methodology study design, comparative method in Sociology, budget for India study, India and Thailand field study recommendations, Vicos-Bang Chan matching questionnaire items c. Goldsen, Rose K.; Ralis, Max; Textor, Robert B. f. outline, correspondence, memorandum, 1955 (Box 12, Folder 33)
    - Census and Qualitative Survey Coding Information
      - a. Vicos: Coding Information b. interviews of rich Vicosinos, seed potato tareas variable code, army veterans, classification system, peones list from 1956, qualitative survey f. notes, outline, list, questionnaire, 1953-1956 (Box 12, Folder 34)
      - a. Seed Potatoes Tarea-Variables Code b. qualitative survey variables, seed potato Tarea variables code drafts, qualitative survey recommended revisions f. outlines, memorandum, 1955 (Box 12, Folder 35)
      - a. Vicos--Card Design and Code Sheets b. qualitative survey coding design f. notes, statistics, lists (Box 12, Folder 36)
      - a. Vicos: Survey Code of Westernization b. qualitative survey coding design f. lists, outline, 1953 (Box 12, Folder 37)
      - a. Vicos Census Code and Qualitative Survey Code b. household census coding design, individual census coding design, qualitative survey coding design, heads of households f. lists, outlines, 1953 (Box 12, Folder 38)
      - a. Coding Material b. household census coding design, individual census coding design f. lists, outlines, print-outs, 1952 (Box 12, Folder 39)
      - a. Coding Sheets for Household Cards b. household census coding design f. outline, statistics (Box 12, Folder 40)
      - a. Print-Out Sheets for Household Census b. household census coding design f. print-outs (Box 12, Folder 41)
  - Field Data from Vicos, Ancash, Peru
    The Cornell Methodology Project field data consists of the field notes from Tareas 1-4, and the qualitative survey data. Included as well are the 1952 census returns, which were analyzed for use by the Methodology Project, although actually collected by the CPP. The field notes and life histories from Tareas 1-4 are arranged alphabetically by interviewers, with miscellaneous data at the end. The field data were collected by the Methodology Project field interviewers, copied from their field note books (cuadernos) and divided into four sections, one for each Tarea (field task). The original chronological order of the interviews has been maintained.
    - Field notes and Life Histories from Tareas 1-4
      - a. Vicos Qualitative Data "Code Book" b. cross-referenced categories, classification system, category definitions f. bound volume, 1954-1955 (Box 11, Folder 39)
      - a. Flores: names found in cuadernos and Tarea #1 b. tareas--names mentioned--correct identifications, case studies c. Flores, Juan Elias f. lists, notes, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 15)
      - a. Flores: Tarea #2 b. case studies c. Flores, Juan Elias f. notes, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 16)
      - a. Flores: Tarea #3 b. case studies c. Flores, Juan Elias f. notes, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 17)
      - a. Flores: Tarea #4 and observation b. case studies, 48 hour observations c. Flores, Juan Elias f. notes, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 18)
      - a. Flores: Tareas duplicates cuadernos 1 & 2 b. project personnel--evaluations, case studies c. Flores, Juan Elias f. notes, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 19)
      - a. Flores: Tareas duplicates cuadernos 3 & 4 b. case studies c. Flores, Juan Elias f. notes, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 20)
      - a. Flores: Tareas duplicates cuadernos 5 & 6 b. case studies, observation in the school c. Flores, Juan Elias f. notes, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 21)
      - a. Flores: Tareas duplicates cuadernos 7 & 8 b. case studies, 48 hour observations c. Flores, Juan Elias f. notes, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 22)
      - a. Gomez: Tarea Life histories b. life histories c. Gomez f. vitae (Box 7, Folder 23)
      - a. Gomez: Life histories, duplicates b. life histories c. Gomez f. vitae (Box 7, Folder 24)
      - a. Gomez: Tarea observations b. 48 hour observations, life history c. Gomez f. notes, vita, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 25)
      - a. Gomez: 48 hour observation duplicate b. 48 hour observation c. Gomez f. notes, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 26)
      - a. Soler: names found in cuadernos and Tarea #1 b. Tareas--names mentioned--correct identifications, case studies c. Soler Bustamante, Eduardo f. notes, lists, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 27)
      - a. Soler: Tarea #1 (Life Histories) and Tarea #2 b. life histories, case studies c. Soler Bustamante, Eduardo f. notes, vitae, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 28)
      - a. Soler: Tarea #3 b. case studies C. Soler Bustamante, Eduardo f. notes, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 29)
      - a. Soler: Tarea #4 and observation b. case studies, spot study, 48 hour observation c. Soler Bustamante, Eduardo f. notes, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 30)
      - a. Soler: Tareas, Duplicates cuadernos 1&2 b. case studies, life histories, observation of a child's funeral c. Soler Bustamante, Eduardo f. notes, vitae, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 31)
      - a. Soler: Tareas Duplicates cuadernos 3&4 b. case studies, 48 hour observations, spot studies, photographs--use in observations c. Soler Bustamante, Eduardo f. report, notes, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 32)
      - a. Soto: Names found in cuadernos and Tarea #1 b. tareas--names mentioned--correct identifications, case studies c. Soto Flores, Froilán f. lists, notes, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 33)
      - a. Soto: Tarea #2 b. case studies c. Soto Flores, Froilán f. notes, 1953 (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - a. Soto: Tarea #3 b. case studies, c. Soto Flores, Froilán f. notes, 1953 (Box 13, Folder 2)
      - a. Soto: Tarea #4 and observation b. case studies, child's funeral--observation, 48 hour observation, 24 hour observation c. Soto Flores, Froilán f. notes, 1953 (Box 13, Folder 3)
      - a. Soto: Tareas Duplicates cuadernos 1&2 b. case studies c. Soto Flores, Froilán f. notes, 1953 (Box 13, Folder 4)
      - a. Soto p. 49-102 Duplicate cuaderno #2 b. case studies c. Soto Flores, Froilán f. notes, 1953 (Box 13, Folder 5)
      - a. Soto: Tareas Duplicates cuadernos 3&4 b. case studies, 24 hour observation, 48 observation c. Soto Flores, Froilán f. notes, 1953 (Box 13, Folder 6)
      - a. Vicos Miscellaneous Field Data b. table of contents--folders 4-7, field work organization, home life--observations--instructions, Vicosino home life--field study c. Barnett, Clifford f. notes, list, minutes, 1953 (Box 13, Folder 7)
      - a. Vicos: Miscellaneous Field Data b. interview evaluation, Mestizo attitude toward Indians, personal data of interviewers, acceptance of innovation, acculturation c. Barnett, Clifford; Estremadoyro, Ricardo; Flores, Juan Elias f. vitae, notes, correspondence, outline, 1953-1954 (Box 13, Folder 8)
      - a. Vicos: Miscellaneous Field Data b. personal data of interviewer, photographs--use in observations, Thematic Apperception Test--response, interview evaluation, tarea evaluation, interpreter evaluation, home life observations--evaluation, survey questionnaire evaluation C. Soler Bustamante, Eduardo; Soto Flores, Froilán f. reports, notes, vitae, 1953 (Box 13, Folder 9)
      - a. Vicos: Miscellaneous Field Data b. interpreter evaluation, tarea evaluation survey pretest, Vicos school--observation c. Flores, Juan Elias f. reports, notes, 1953 (Box 13, Folder 10)
      - a. Interviews and Life Histories b. Mestizo attitude toward Indians, recorded interview evaluation c. Estremadoyro, Ricardo; Boluarte, Francisco f. notes, reports, 1953 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - 1952 Census Forms
      - a. Census Forms b. respondents #1-43 f. census forms, 1952 (Box 13, Folder 12)
      - a. Census Forms b. respondents #44-84 f. census forms, 1952 (Box 13, Folder 13)
      - a. Census forms b. respondents #85-111 f. census forms, 1952 (Box 13, Folder 14)
      - a. Census Forms b. respondents #112-149 f. census forms, 1952 (Box 13, Folder 15)
      - a. Census forms b. respondents #150-187 f. census forms, 1952 (Box 13, Folder 16)
      - a. Census forms b. respondents #188-225 f. census forms, 1952 (Box 13, Folder 17)
      - a. Census forms b. respondents #226-241 f. census forms, 1952 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Qualitative Survey Interviews
      - a. Survey Interviews b. respondents 000-103 f. questionnaires, 1953; 99 folders (Box 15)
      - a. Survey Interviews b. respondents 104-208 f. questionnaires, 1953; 105 folders (Box 16)
      - a. Survey Interviews b. respondents 209-282 f. questionnaires, 1953; 75 folders (Box 17)
- Series V. Miscellaneous Files
  These materials came to the archives along with the materials comprising Series II. Cornell Peru Project (Accession 2). They have no obvious connection to Allan Holmberg's work in Peru.
  - Pamphlet: Report: On the Discovery of Documents which Reveal the Negro Slave Trade among the Lower-class Indians during the Viceregal Government in Perú, Emilio Harth-terré (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Pamphlet: Aspectos Generales de la Situacion Economica y Financiera del Peru (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Pamphlet: Hacienda, Peonaje y Servidumbre en los Andes Peruanos, Mario C. Vasquez (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Pamphlet: Política Educativa del Estado Peruano, Gustavo Pons Muzzo (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Professional correspondence (Box 17, Folder 76)
  - "Highland South America," essay (Box 17, Folder 77)
  - Notes on Knight Biggerstaff's seminar in Far Eastern Studies, 1948-1949 (Box 17, Folder 78)
  - Rural electrification, 1961-1962 (Box 17, Folder 79)
  - Figures and Maps for the Religious Festival (Sonora, Mexico), Henry F. Dobyns (Box 17, Folder 80)
- Separated Materials
  Materials in this section were separated from their original folders because they are oversize. The original folder contains a separation sheet noting the former location of the item and where it is now housed.
  - Vicos - topographic map of the Marcara region (CPP), December 1963; Series II. Cornell Peru Project (Accession 2): Gary Vescelius correspondence, 1963-1965 (Mapcase-folder 1)
  - Plano de los Terrenos Cedidos a la Escuela Rural Prevocacional, May 1956; Series II. Cornell Peru Project (Accession 2): Vicos-Education, 1950s (Mapcase-folder 1)
  - Museo Archeologico blueprint, 1964; Series II. Cornell Peru Project (Accession 2): Gary Vescelius correspondence, 1963-1965 (Mapcase-folder 1)
  - Hacienda Vicos map, Robert Stevens, 1954; Series I. Cornell Peru Project (Accession 1): Reprints, Publications and Papers - Scientific Reports (Mapcase-folder 1)
  - Viva Sano poster, Ministerio de Salud Publica y Asistencia Social, Series II. Cornell Peru Project (Accession 2): School lunch, 1955 (Mapcase-folder 1)
  - Censo Antropologico de la Hacienda Vicos, 1959; Series II. Cornell Peru Project (Accession 2): Vicos-census, 1959 (Mapcase-folder 1)